<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All Posts - Maxime Nemo Website</title>
        <link>https://maximene.github.io/posts/</link>
        <description>All Posts | Maxime Nemo Website</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>Maxime.Nemo@grenoble-inp.org (Maxime NEMO)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>Maxime.Nemo@grenoble-inp.org (Maxime NEMO)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 21:02:41 &#43;0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://maximene.github.io/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Ens&#39;IA association</title>
    <link>https://maximene.github.io/posts/ensia/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 21:02:41 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://maximene.github.io/posts/ensia/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[What is Ens&rsquo;IA Ens&rsquo;IA is a french AI association aiming to :
Promote AI and its applications Organize with partners, companies or other student associations events and activities such as conferences, lectures, training workshops, collaborative workshops, professional-student meetings, etc. Organize AI competitions and challenges in France Promoting ethical and responsible AI You can find the free courses we offer on our github page
My work at Ens&rsquo;IA for 2021-2022 I am the vice-president of the association.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Research internship - Direction du Numérique Université de Bourgogne</title>
    <link>https://maximene.github.io/posts/stage_nlp/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 21:01:41 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://maximene.github.io/posts/stage_nlp/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I worked as an intern for the Direction du Numérique of the Université de Bourgogne for 10 weeks. It was the perfect oportunity for me to work on a real project and to learn more about what is research, but also to learn more about AI, and especially NLP.
The first project I was asked to create a new dataset about tourism to upgrade the idiomaticity of an animated conversational agent that will be used in the 2024 Paris Olympic Games.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Introduction to research - Analysis by Supervised Learning of CT images of pelvic fractures</title>
    <link>https://maximene.github.io/posts/irl/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 10:29:41 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://maximene.github.io/posts/irl/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[What is that ? I had the chance to work on a real project during my studies. It was about the analysis of CT images of pelvic fractures.
I worked one afternoon per week during one semester in the TIMC laboratory in the GMCAO team.
Abstract Acetabular fracture (cavity in the pelvis where the head of the femur is located), generally require a CT scan to locate and classify the fractures according to their type, according to the Letournel classification.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Android App project - React Native | Ensimag&#39;s Project</title>
    <link>https://maximene.github.io/posts/android_app/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 10:29:41 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://maximene.github.io/posts/android_app/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The project The project was done in a team of 5 people. The goal was to deliver an Android App together with a test benchmark, a complete documentation and a functionnal backend.
More about the project The App should allow users to create stories and share them with others. The idea is that after each paragraph, an action can be taken and then, it leads to a new paragraph. Everyone can create new paragraphs, read stories etc&hellip; depending on the permissions they have.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Ens&#39;IA : Reinforcement Learning course</title>
    <link>https://maximene.github.io/posts/ensia_rl/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 11:05:23 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://maximene.github.io/posts/ensia_rl/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Introduction As a member of Ens&rsquo;IA, I give lectures and lab works about artificial intelligence.
In 2021/2022, @Hugo Cartigny and I gave lectures and lab works about
Machine Learning with KNN and K-Means Deep learning in computer vision (perceptron, sigmoid neuron, neural networks, convolutional neural nerworks &hellip;) Data processing for computer vision As you can see, we did not talk about Reinforcement Learning yet, so I dicided to build a course about it, especially about Q-Learning]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>BlowWar AI | Ensimag&#39;s Project</title>
    <link>https://maximene.github.io/posts/blob_war/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 11:05:23 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://maximene.github.io/posts/blob_war/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The game Blobwar is played on an 8x8 chessboard where two players (blue and red) compete. Each player has a set of pieces called blobs. The game is played turn by turn. Each turn, whenever possible, the current player chooses a blob and moves it. Any move to an adjacent square (including diagonally) sees the blob duplicated on the target square. It is also possible to jump to a distance of 2 squares, but in this case the blob moves from the starting square to the target square (so there is no duplication).]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Challenge Neovision x Ens&#39;IA 2022</title>
    <link>https://maximene.github.io/posts/challenge2022/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 10:29:41 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://maximene.github.io/posts/challenge2022/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[What is this challenge about? This is an artificial intelligence challenge organized jointly by Neovision and Ens&rsquo;IA. For the second edition of this challenge, participants had to create an AI, but don&rsquo;t panic: Neovision coaches will were there to accompany them. There were also workshops to give them additional knowledge!
This challenge were for participants the opportunity to live a real AI project and to deepen their knowledge, but also and above all to have fun and to meet people]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Software engineering project | Ensimag&#39;s Project</title>
    <link>https://maximene.github.io/posts/projet_gl/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 21:01:41 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://maximene.github.io/posts/projet_gl/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[What is the project about ? The goal is to build in Java a compiler with no default for a language called Deca (Java like language)
The compilation process is divided into 3 steps :
The syntax analysis (Lexer and Parser) input : source program output : primitive abstract tree The contextual verification input : primitive abstract tree output : abstract tree decorated The code generation for an abstract machine input : abstract tree decorated output : assembly program Finally, the project is also composed of a theme of our choice.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Database for an e-commerce company | Ensimag&#39;s Project</title>
    <link>https://maximene.github.io/posts/database_project/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 10:29:41 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://maximene.github.io/posts/database_project/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The project The e-commerce company for individuals, Gange, wants us to set up a database to better manage the products they offer for sale.
The sales are based auction mode:
Users make increasing bids on available products and the 5th bid wins. The auction mode is not important, it can should changed easily, and is not known by Gange&rsquo;s customers. The products are categorized and and a recommendation mode should be implemented.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Multi-agent simulators | Ensimag&#39;s Project</title>
    <link>https://maximene.github.io/posts/simulators/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 21:01:41 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://maximene.github.io/posts/simulators/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The project With two teamates, we implemented 5 different multi-agent simulators using only java.
Every simulator we implemented is using an event manager to handle the execution of the next step of the simulation.
Balls simulator Ball simulator in action Cellular simulators Conway&rsquo;s game of life. Conway's game of life in action Immigration game Immigration game simulator Schelling model Schelling model simulator Boids simulator Boid simulator What is a boid simulator?]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
