<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All Posts - Maxime Nemo Website</title>
        <link>https://maximene.github.io/posts/</link>
        <description>All Posts | Maxime Nemo Website</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>max71ne@gmail.com (Maxime NEMO)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>max71ne@gmail.com (Maxime NEMO)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 10:29:41 &#43;0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://maximene.github.io/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Log Analysis Application Development Project</title>
    <link>https://maximene.github.io/posts/log_analysis/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 10:29:41 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://maximene.github.io/posts/log_analysis/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Summary of the Log Analysis Application Development Project This project is focused on developing an internal application for log analysis using Machine Learning (ML).
Context and Motivation With the exponential growth of digital services, log analysis has become an increasingly important area of study. Logs are generated in massive quantities by various systems, making manual analysis infeasible. Automated tools are necessary to manage these logs effectively. The goal of the project was to develop an internal solution capable of analyzing logs to monitor the state of SOLUTEC’s IT systems and detect anomalies in internal systems under development.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Challenge Open Data | Ensimag&#39;s project</title>
    <link>https://maximene.github.io/posts/opendata/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 10:29:41 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://maximene.github.io/posts/opendata/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Description The goal is to create a data visualization of an open data set.
Results Click here to go on the page]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>IOT project : Ambilight | Ensimag&#39;s project</title>
    <link>https://maximene.github.io/posts/iot-project/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 10:29:41 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://maximene.github.io/posts/iot-project/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Introduction Ambilite is the ideal solution to improve your viewing experience. Thanks to our technology, you can synchronize the LEDs behind your screen with the image displayed the displayed image for a total immersion in your movie or video. Our product is similar to Philips Ambilight technology, but is compatible with all screens, unlike Ambilight which is only available on some TVs or with an HDMI adapter which HDMI adapter which limits functionality and adds latency.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Les nouvelles technologies en IA vont impacter beaucoup de métiers | [French only]</title>
    <link>https://maximene.github.io/posts/new_tech_in_ai/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 08:02:41 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://maximene.github.io/posts/new_tech_in_ai/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Si vous êtes comme moi et que vous vous intéressez un petit peu à l&rsquo;IA, vous avez probablement entendu parler d&rsquo;IA super-puissantes, notamment GPT-3 ou DALL-E 2.
Pour ceux qui ne savent pas de quoi il s&rsquo;agit, je vais faire une rapide présentation de ce que sont ces deux modèles d&rsquo;intelligence artificielle, et de ce dont ils sont capables.
OpenAI, une des entreprises majeures en IA, a récemment sorti deux modèles à couper le souffle nommés GPT-3 et DALL-E 2, respectivement les successeurs de GPT-2 et DALL-E.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Why I quit google analytics and how I replaced it</title>
    <link>https://maximene.github.io/posts/personnal_website/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 21:02:41 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://maximene.github.io/posts/personnal_website/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[What is GDPR (RGPD in french) and why it&rsquo;s important ? GDPR is a regulation in EU law on data protection and privacy in the European Union and the European Economic Area (EEA). It also addresses the transfer of personal data outside the EU and EEA. It applies to all companies that offer goods or services to people in the EU, or that monitor the behavior of people in the EU.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Ens&#39;IA association</title>
    <link>https://maximene.github.io/posts/ensia/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 21:02:41 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://maximene.github.io/posts/ensia/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[What is Ens&rsquo;IA Ens&rsquo;IA is a french AI association aiming to :
Promote AI and its applications Organize with partners, companies or other student associations events and activities such as conferences, lectures, training workshops, collaborative workshops, professional-student meetings, etc. Organize AI competitions and challenges in France Promoting ethical and responsible AI You can find the free courses we offer on our github page
My work at Ens&rsquo;IA for 2021-2022 I am the vice-president of the association.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Research internship - Direction du Numérique Université de Bourgogne</title>
    <link>https://maximene.github.io/posts/stage_nlp/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 21:01:41 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://maximene.github.io/posts/stage_nlp/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I worked as an intern for the Direction du Numérique of the Université de Bourgogne for 10 weeks. It was the perfect oportunity for me to work on a real project and to learn more about what is research, but also to learn more about AI, and especially NLP.
The first project I was asked to create a new dataset about tourism to upgrade the idiomaticity of an animated conversational agent that will be used in the 2024 Paris Olympic Games.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Introduction to research - Analysis by Supervised Learning of CT images of pelvic fractures</title>
    <link>https://maximene.github.io/posts/irl/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 10:29:41 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://maximene.github.io/posts/irl/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[What is that ? I had the chance to work on a real project during my studies. It was about the analysis of CT images of pelvic fractures.
I worked one afternoon per week during one semester in the TIMC laboratory in the GMCAO team.
Abstract Acetabular fracture (cavity in the pelvis where the head of the femur is located), generally require a CT scan to locate and classify the fractures according to their type, according to the Letournel classification.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Android App project - React Native | Ensimag&#39;s Project</title>
    <link>https://maximene.github.io/posts/android_app/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 10:29:41 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://maximene.github.io/posts/android_app/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The project The project was done in a team of 5 people. The goal was to deliver an Android App together with a test benchmark, a complete documentation and a functionnal backend.
More about the project The App should allow users to create stories and share them with others. The idea is that after each paragraph, an action can be taken and then, it leads to a new paragraph. Everyone can create new paragraphs, read stories etc&hellip; depending on the permissions they have.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Ens&#39;IA : Reinforcement Learning course</title>
    <link>https://maximene.github.io/posts/ensia_rl/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 11:05:23 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://maximene.github.io/posts/ensia_rl/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Introduction As a member of Ens&rsquo;IA, I give lectures and lab works about artificial intelligence.
In 2021/2022, @Hugo Cartigny and I gave lectures and lab works about
Machine Learning with KNN and K-Means Deep learning in computer vision (perceptron, sigmoid neuron, neural networks, convolutional neural nerworks &hellip;) Data processing for computer vision As you can see, we did not talk about Reinforcement Learning yet, so I dicided to build a course about it, especially about Q-Learning]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
